permissionmedia.com 2004-06-04

# EmailUniverse.com Privacy Statement

EmailUniverse.com Privacy Statement

Subscription Forms

EmailUniverse.com uses subscription forms for individuals to request information by subscribing to Email Newsletters based on their categories of interest. We collect visitor's contact information (like your email address) to provide you with the information that you request. We will periodically send you email referring to news and updates to EmailUniverse.com.

Choice / OPT-IN

We provide opt-in opportunities for all email lists that you choose to receive. We use your email addresses to confirm your subscription and validity of the provided email address. Your reply to this email is necessary for completing your subscription to any email list.

IP address

We use your IP address, browser type, domain names, and access times, operating system, country of origin, page views, and users sessions to help diagnose problems with our servers, and to administer our Web site. Your IP, etc. address is used to gather broad demographic information.

Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer. Our site only uses session ID cookies so our advertisement server can deliver proper ad rotation sequences. For example, if three banners are in rotation, the individual gets the proper rotation without duplicates. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to personally identifiable information while on our site. Further, once a user closes their browser the cookie simply terminates.

Links

This site contains links to other sites. EmailUniverse.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. EmailUniverse.com recommends you refer to each Network Member's Privacy Statements.

Sharing Information

EmailUniverse.com does not share, sell or rent your email addresses to outside third parties. See our Third Party Information/List Referral Section below. Personally identifiable information will only be disclosed due to law or court demands (see our legal disclaimer below for more information)..

Supplementation of Information

We do not supplement your personally identifiable information with any outside third parties information.

Security

The EmailUniverse.com web site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Sensitive data, such as credit card information, collected through EmailUniverse.com's website is transferred via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) server only. EmailUniverse.com employees are made aware of all security policies and are maintaining and protecting your personally identifiable information.

Correct / Update

Change the email address that you have subscribed with by first unsubscribing with your current email address. Then, resubscribe with your new email address. All email list welcome messages contain the information necessary for subscription and removal from their appropriate list.

Permission Request Form

All information collected via the Permission Request Form for copyrighted materials is used by EmailUniverse.com to identify the requesting entity and respond to their request. The users' personally identifiable information is not given to third-parties.

Unsubscribe

We provide unsubscribe/opt-out opportunities for all email lists that you choose to receive. All email list welcome messages contain the information necessary for removal from the list. Removal from all lists is instant and automated by our servers.

Third Party Information/List Referrals

EmailUniverse has partnered with PostMaster Direct to provide our list owners another venue for revenue generation with their lists.

Under our standard management agreement, we provide you with forms and list infrastructure via our site, and you just direct visitors to the forms. When new subscribers sign up via your form, the names are added to your lists. Your lists become available for rental via our site. We provide marketing, mailing, merge/purge, and subscribe/unsubscribe services.

**End users:** Your name, email address, zipcode and any other identifying information that you give us will not be revealed to any of the direct marketers who rent our lists. When you sign up for the PostMasterDirect.com mailing lists, you will receive commercial email messages only about those topical categories that you have selected. Before any mailing goes out, their staff personally screens each marketer's message to make sure that it's relevant to the list's topic.

Every PostMasterDirect.com message sent out is coded with a special header and footer that allows you to remove your name from all lists automatically by forwarding the message to [deleteall@postmasterdirect.com](mailto:deleteall@postmasterdirect.com).

Surveys

The email addresses and contact information collected via publisher surveys are used solely to compile general statistical data. The users' personally identifiable information is never sold or given out to parties outside EmailUniverse.com. All information is collected via the online form provided.

Notification of Changes

EmailUniverse.com will occasionally update our Privacy Policy based on our employees' and users' feedback. If there are any material changes to how we use your personal information, we will notify via email and provide you the opportunity to opt-out prior to any substantial change that has been taken. However, if you have opted out of all communication from EmailUniverse.com you will not be contacted, nor will your personal information be used in this new manner. EmailUniverse.com encourages you to periodically review our privacy policy to be informed of how we are committed to protecting your privacy.

Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our Web site.

Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:

EmailUniverse.com Privacy Team  
c/o Christopher Knight  
http://EmailUniverse.com/  
PO Box 12740  
Green Bay, WI 54307
